In this clip on how to audition for a Broadway play, I'm going to talk about how to pick an appropriate monologue for a specific audition that you're going to.
If we continue on this example of "Three Changes", by Nicky Silver, and I'm going in for Steffi, mid to late twenties, garish, somewhat dim-witted young woman; works at the Clinique, and romantically involved with Nate.
So I'm going to find, because it's, look at the playwright, Nicky Silver.
This is a comedic contemporary playwright; you know, very wordy, the humor is in the words.
It's very clever and wordy, fast-paced, so I would definitely pick a contemporary comedic monologue.
I could even do another Nick Nicky Silver monologue.
It's good to have a Nicky Silver in your repertoire, if it fits you.
So she plays something romantic.
It might be good to pick something that involves a monologue that talks about romance, something a little romantic.
Even if you have a monologue that is about something completely different, I mean open your mind, and think outside the box.
Can this monologue be turned into this character a little bit?
You know, you might have a monologue about washing your clothes, but if you do it in a garish, romantic, somewhat dim-witted way, suddenly you're Steffi.
So find that monologue, but also transform that monologue into the character.